Now let's look carefully at the graph we have obtained underneath.
现在我们仔细看看下面获得的图表
This is what's called a model complexity graph.
这称为模型复杂度图
Notice that on the left we have a model that underfits, and
注意左侧是一个欠拟合模型
gives us high training and testing errors.
它具有较高的训练误差和测试误差
The model on the right overfits, and
右边的模型过拟合
it gives us a very low training error, but a high testing error.
它具有较低的训练误差和较高的测试误差
The model in the middle is just right, and
中间的模型刚刚好
it gives us relatively low training and testing errors.
它给我们相对较低的训练和测试误差
This is the model we should pick.
这是我们应该选择的模型
So here we have a bit of a clearer picture.
这里我们可以看得更清楚
In the x axis we have the complexity of the model.
x 轴是模型的复杂度
So we go from linear, degree 1, all the way to polynomial, degree 4.
我们的模型从线性到一次多项式一直到四次多项式
On the left the models show underfitting or high bias error.
左侧模型显示了欠拟合或高偏差误差
On the right We see overfitting, or high variance error.
右侧的显示了过拟合或者说高方差误差
And in the middle, around the value 2 there is a happy point
而在中间 2 的位置是最佳点
where we are neither underfitting nor overfitting.
这里既不欠拟合 也不过拟合
Thus, we decided the best model for our data is a polynomial of degree 2.
因此 可以确定我们数据的最佳模型是二次多项式
So far so good, right?
目前一切都还不错 对吧？
Whats happening?
什么情况？
What is this?
这是怎么回事？发生什么了？
No, what do we do?
我们该怎么做？
We broke the golden rule.
原来我们违背了一条黄金法则
You should never use your testing data for training.
永远不能将测试数据用于训练
We made a huge mistake.
我们犯了一个严重的错误
But let's see, what did we do here?
但是来看看 我们到底做了什么？
Here is the problem.
问题在这里
We used our testing data to train our model.
我们用测试数据训练了模型
We're not supposed to use our testing data until the very end.
除非到最后一步 我们不应该使用测试数据
And we used it to make a huge decision about our model.
但我们却利用它决定了我们选择的模型
This is completely forbidden.
这是完全禁止的
You're not allowed to touch your testing data.
你是不允许触碰测试数据的
So how do we fix this?
那么我们如何解决这个问题呢？
How do we make a good decision about our model without using the testing data?
我们如何在不使用测试数据的情况下 对模型做出正确的选择呢？
Well, no need to panic.
不用慌
We can fix this by breaking our data set even more.
我们可以进一步拆分数据集来解决这个问题
Now, instead of having a training and
现在 除了训练集和
a testing set, we'll add a cross validation set.
测试集 我们还将添加一个交叉验证集
Now, the training set will be used for training the parameters.
训练集将用于训练参数
The cross validation set will be used for
交叉验证集将用于
making decisions about the model, such as the degree of the polynomial.
对模型做出决定 例如多项式的次数
And the testing set will be used for the final testing of the model.
测试集将用于模型的最终测试
Now our graph looks so
现在我们的图表看起来好多了
much nicer with a cross validation error instead of a testing error.
包含交叉验证误差 而不是测试误差
So let's recap.
我们来回顾一下
Here we have the model complexity graph and the example all together.
这里我们将模型复杂性图和示例放在一起
On the left, we see underfitting or an oversimplification of the problem. Here we have the model complexity graph and the example all together.
在左边 我们看到的是欠拟合
On the left, we see underfitting or an oversimplification of the problem.
或者说过度简化问题
This is bad on both the training and the cross validation set
这对训练集和交叉验证集来说都很糟
because our model simply does not capture the complexity of our data.
因为我们的模型根本无法捕捉数据的复杂性
On the right, we see overfitting or an over complication of the problem.
在右侧 我们看到的是过拟合或过度复杂化问题
This is great on the training set, because we are memorizing it, but On the right, we see overfitting or an over complication of the problem.
在对训练集的拟合效果较好
This is great on the training set, because we are memorizing it, but
因为模型在记住它
bad on the cross validation set because the model does not generalize well.
但对交叉验证的效果较差 因为模型不能很好地泛化
And in the middle we have the perfect model which is good in both the training
中间是我们的完美模型 它在训练集
and the testing set.
和测试集上的拟合效果都很好
I like to imagine underfitting as coming to an exam unprepared.
我们可以将欠拟合想象成在无准备的情况下去参加考试
No matter how hard you try you won't do well.
无论你费多大的力 最终都考不好
Overfitting is like studying for an exam but instead of
过拟合是做了准备 但是
trying to understand the material, you just memorize the book word by word.
你没有去理解那些知识 只是将它一字一句地背下来了
You can repeat anything that's given, but
你可以回答得上试卷上所有重复的问题
you won't be able to answer new questions about the data.
但遇到关于数据的新问题 就答不出来了
A good model is like studying for an exam and
而完美的模型就像是你学习了知识
coming ready to answer any questions in the material.
并准备好回答试卷中遇到的任何新问题
And here is just a general picture of the model complexity graph.
这里是模型复杂度的一般图形
Of course they may not look as pretty, but in real life you see that most of
当然 它们可能没这么漂亮 但在现实生活中的大多数时候
the time your models will exhibit a behavior like this one.
你的模型都会表现出这样的行为
Wheres the model gets more complex, the training error gets smaller and smaller.
模型越复杂 训练误差越来越小
And the testing error starts big, then decreases and then increases again.
测试误差开始很大 然后减小 然后再变大
On the left you underfit.
左侧欠拟合
On the right, you overfit.
右侧过拟合
And the perfect point is here,
而完美点在这里
where the graphs just start to distance from each other.
图形开始互相远离